Welcome to The EcommOps podcast. My name is
Simon. I'm here today with my co-hosts Dayu
and Greg Lepkoff. This podcast is all
about your supply chain from China and
we as EcommOps decided to really focus
on the fulfillment and moved away more
and more from the sourcing for good reasons.
Sourcing is a completely different game for
DTC brands. Finding a product in China is easy,
but you also not only compete with Aliexpress,
but you're actually competing
with players like Temu as well.
You're basically forced to customize
your brand and develop your product and
offering. For that reason. We have
a guest speaker. Tune in, listen,
and like and share if you like it as well. And
then I hope you enjoy the episode. We’re very
pleased today to have a guest speaker. Our first
guest of The EcommOps Podcast is an honor. It's
a great partner of ours. From Kanary Solutions,
we have Greg Lepkoff. Welcome to the show, man.
Thanks. Appreciate it. Thanks for having me.
This is really cool to have us actually
teaming up on this podcast, but also outside
of this podcast because your focus for the last
probably twelve years, correct me if I'm wrong,
you have been sourcing from China, and
just like me, China has became a part of
your life. Can you share a little bit more on
how you grew into the role you're playing now?
Yeah, sure. So when I was graduating college
around 2008, I was an East Asian Studies major,
mainly so I could just write papers and not take
tests. But when I graduated, I moved out to China,
lived with a Chinese family, and got fluent in
the language. I always wanted to do business and I
just didn't know which area to fall into. So when
I moved out there, I was just working with a lot
of different types of companies and seeing how I
could be like a bridge between the US and China.
And I kind of just fell into sourcing and
helping companies in the US manufacture
products in China. So I lived in China for
a total of ten years, and now I go there,
of course, for my work now a couple of times
a year. And we have an office and everything
in Shenzhen and built a really solid team. So now
we're sourcing primarily for ecommerce DTC brands.
So can you share a little bit more about
Kanary Solutions? You're based in the US,
but obviously, it's not just
you, right? There's a whole
team and structure built around
the business of sourcing itself.
Correct. My partner, John McDougall, and I manage
the clients. And then we have our partner Jerry,
who's in China. He manages our account
reps. So we have two teams in China. One
is doing manufacturer supplier research, and
then the other team is managing our clients
more on the day-to-day side. So just, like,
confirming details of designs, packaging,
lead times, and just like, getting them as
ready as possible to place their orders,
but also trigger them about stuff that's ongoing
with their order and things of that nature.
And then we have our operations in
the Philippines just to handle a
lot of order tracking, inventory tracking,
shipment updates for the clients that we're
doing bulk shipping to 3PL providers
in the US. Of course, with you guys,
they're kind of a little bit part of the
process for getting shipments over to you.
Hey, Greg. So we've known each other for a very
long time, and actually, your business structure
actually sounds quite similar to how we have it at
EcommOps. This mixture of having a China team on
the ground and also having. Not sure it's very
obvious, but a Western perspective between you
and Simon and myself as well. So before we get
into the actual supply chain management of it,
I'd love to kind of hear your experience kind
of straddling the Chinese business culture
and Western business expectations as well, and
how you've navigated that with your business.
Yeah, that's a very good question, I think
from living in China for as long as I have,
one of my main focuses on living there and
learning the language. I was also learning
the culture, which required me to really just
be a sponge. Just do the partying when you're
supposed to party with them. Meaning have drinks
with them, smoke cigarettes with them. I mean,
it's building a relationship that was,
at the core, what it was all about.
And then when I started sourcing, I kind of had
some of those, that foundation of experience.
So now I'm building relationships with my
manufacturers, learning about when the right
times are to discuss pricing issues or lead
time issues. But really what's most important
about everything is getting that Facetime with
them and being able to work with them and make
sure that they're flexible with you so that when I
turn around and deal with the clients in the West,
it's easier for me to explain what's
going on and be transparent about it.
That way they don't feel like there's
gray areas or any kind of gameplay.
Yeah, that's great. And the reason why I
asked that is because before we even talk
about any technical aspects of sourcing or
fulfillment, I think a fundamental critical
element is for someone who is a Western brand,
who's more used to that Western culture,
to be able to bridge that gap working with
China-based operations, whether it's factories
or fulfillment as well. And I will just say
that I'm Chinese, but I grew up in the US.
There's so many fundamental differences between
the business cultures, between both. And this is
something that I've known you for a while, Greg,
and I think this is something that both you and I,
and also. Simon, very aware of, that a great
sourcing agent, a great fulfillment agent,
is more around that relationship and knowing
how to navigate on the ground in China,
but also knowing how to translate that in
the right way and communicate with
our mostly Western clients as well.
Yeah, let's go into that, because maybe we
could just kick off with, can you just break
down maybe the sourcing process in some stages?
And what do you see as main pitfalls that might
arise in these stages? Because it's not just,
this is what I want, and then it's delivered.
Yeah, no problem. So I'm going to break
it down into five areas. The fifth area is
kind of the shipping element. So in terms
of sourcing as like a sourcing company,
the first stage is always due diligence, right.
So the due diligence process, like when a client
comes to us about a product that they want
us to help them produce with a manufacturer,
we typically speak to about 30 to 50 companies
in the industry that like the product niche.
I say companies because when you're doing your
due diligence, you actually don't know which are
factories and which are trade companies. Or they
might be a factory that's producing one product,
but offering you another product that they buy
from another factory and reselling it to. So,
like, during this due diligence process, I'd
say that's kind of one of the pitfalls is like,
you don't really know who you're working
with. Is it a factory? Is it a trade company?
It's very easy for companies on Alibaba
to make themselves appear like they're
the factory. So that would be like, the due
diligence aspect of it, sampling. As you know,
everyone needs to order samples before
they place a bulk order. So I would say
just like a pitfall with that process is,
I mean, first of all, you should always get
samples from multiple vendors so that
you can compare and contrast quality.
But I'd say the big issue is more about not asking
your final candidates. You got samples from, like,
enough questions about the samples to see
which one can make the most improvements.
Sometimes you order samples, and
maybe one of them had, I don't know,
a scratch and the other one didn't. So you're
choosing that other product because it didn't
have a scratch. But what you don't know is,
let's just say it's an electronics product.
They have a better engineering team, they
can do more product development for you,
or they could handle your customization
issues. So sometimes people just assume
things when they look at the product, when
they need to be talking to a company like us,
to kind of say, hey, is this really a big deal?
The scratch that was on the electronics product.
So actually, Greg, actually, I want to
talk about those first two points. First,
because they're quite interesting
because between Simon and myself,
we've had a lot of experience in the
drop shipping space. And if you think
about due diligence or even the first step
of due diligence. Right, due diligence in
traditional drop shipping is what? Finding ten
different Aliexpress links and researching them.
So even the fact that you're talking about not
only looking at 30 to 50 options or more than
ten even, but you're literally talking about
going to the companies or trade companies or
factories themselves, that's just like a
fundamental difference that I think a lot
of dropshippers or early DTC ecommerce brand
owners, you really have to have that kind of
mindset if you really want to have the right,
either the best quality or the most efficient
production for your products as well. And
that goes into this idea of sampling, right?
I remember from my experience with a lot of
traditional dropshippers, typically, well,
there's no sampling in traditional drop shipping.
The sampling comes after the fact. The sampling
comes after you start selling and you finally
get your own sample, and that's your sample,
and then you figure out how to fix it if there's
something wrong with it. So I just want to chime
in, sorry, to interrupt that, I just want to kind
of chime in and just really highlight the contrast
that I see from a more established sourcing
process for you to see ecommerce brand versus
what I really think is a limited approach
to traditional dropshipping sourcing.
That's correct. I think due diligence is key
because this is the beginning phase of our
relationship-building with the manufacturers
as well. When we deal with consumer products,
we're in Shenzhen, so everybody's in
our backyard. So it's kind of quite
easy to just do five visits in a day with a
manufacturer, meet the owners, eat with them,
and kind of just know what their capabilities
are, understand the brands that they're working
with because sometimes it's important to have
an idea of it so that you could see where you
would fall on the totem pole. Like how much of
a priority are you really going to be with the
manufacturer? So while doing this due diligence,
we really are trying to figure out what's the
right fit for the company based on the volumes
that they'll be purchasing or scaling into.
Or should they just be working with a smaller
manufacturer and then scale into another
one at a later time because they'll get more
preferential treatment? Something like that.
Fourth step would just be quality control. I think
one of the pitfalls there is that most customers
dealing directly with China don't really have a
QC checklist system in place with the supplier.
And that's what we have to do day in, day
out. We have to make sure that we're getting
updates from the manufacturer when materials are
coming in when they're going to start assembly.
How are they handling the QC process after?
Are they going to be sending us our pictures
and videos so we could provide it to
the clients? A lot of our DTC brands
want the video so they can use it for
marketing. So we try to get them as the
best possible pictures of either an assembly
line or we have some products that are just
more machine-made and less like a manual
process. So get them pictures of that so
that they could really show that their stuff
is getting produced at a high-quality factory.
So I'd say the quality control part, just
having a good checklist and having a good
process with the manufacturer and making them
work in the system that works best for you on
top of their own QC systems is like the
perfect recipe for success with them.
Would you recommend to also have
during production quality control?
So not just only when the product is
finished, but would you send people
over already during the production as well
to check in if everything’s going smoothly?
When we're doing skincare products, we're
sending pictures and videos of the bottles
getting made. Pictures and videos of the bottles
being filled with skincare products. So, yeah,
we try to be proactive with the supplier to
provide us with those videos and pictures.
It's typically from their phone, but they're
kind of used to that. Surprisingly enough,
I think they do get asked by other people as well.
So that's just something that we always
try to do just so that they know that
their stuff is being made, they know it's
being made in a clean place. So, yeah,
I think it's really valuable to be getting those
QC updates during production, not just after.
Yeah. Think about the thing about quality
control is that it's such an integral part
of just product quality. So it's important
to realize that for the exact same product,
even if they use the exact same tooling,
the same process, the same materials,
if you don't have quality control at all, in
the extreme, that's where you're going to have
quality issues. Every single production line
is going to have some rate of quality issues.
And the really great factories, the ones that
have very strict quality control guidelines,
and they're very careful about things, they're
the ones where the final product at a much higher
rate is going to provide you with the kind
of quality that you're actually looking for.
So this is actually one of the reasons why I
actually suggest that if you're working with
a sourcing agent with a factory, you want to be
careful not to push them too hard, because if you
try to push them too hard—and Greg, maybe kind
of chime in on this—but sometimes if you're just
kind of forcing them to make that tough decision
between timing and putting in the right steps
to make sure that comes out at a high quality,
then that's where you're going to have problems.
And in a way, it's not going to
be the factory's fault as well.
Yeah, I agree.
I think for us, whenever we work with factories,
it's all about setting the right expectations.
You do have to have a bit of flexibility
working within their framework. But during
that due diligence process for us, we're striving
to find factories that have top-notch QC systems.
That way, we just know whenever we're asking.
For example, if we're scaling up a DTC brand
that's going from 20,000 to 100,000 units, in
those situations, we need production schedules.
Anyone that we work with in
general, on the factory side,
they give us that information before we even start
the scale, like, the client starts the scaling.
So. it's just important to make sure you're
working with quality people, and then you can kind
of work within their system so that you're set up
for success. I mean, I think the inquiries we have
to do on the QC side, it's really to just make the
client feel a lot better and feel like everything
is safe, because it doesn't matter how many
times I tell them that it's a top notch factory,
they still don't know if it is or not. They have
no idea. They don't know how the process works.
So it's really just more for the
client to just be like, hey, look,
here's some videos and pictures
of how they're doing things,
and these are their suggestions for trying to do
things a little bit faster without sacrificing
the quality. And the client typically leaves
it in our hands to make the decisions. They
just kind of let us know the criteria before an
order starts. But, yeah, that's my two cents.
Okay, good stuff, Greg. So, basically, due
diligence, your factory selection, sampling,
you get negotiation order confirmation,
and obviously, the quality control.
And the last step probably would be the
shipping, which obviously is something
that we take care of for DTC brands. Obviously,
there's always a mix between doing it by boat,
by train, sometimes even if it's mainland
or close to China, and obviously by air.
Definitely, these shipping options are always
there, and it really depends on what's the
best fit. So definitely also something that
I would say is part of the sourcing process
of knowing how you want it to be shipped out.
That's definitely an aspect that is come into
play when it comes to sourcing from China
as well. You want to do a full container,
you want to do in batches, or you want part of it,
maybe fast by air to a location of your choice.
It's definitely something that you need to take
care of as like a fifth step to consider. What I
would like to know actually from you is you've
dealt with so many factories and suppliers,
and I always get the people that are dealing
with China, they're always wondering, like:
‘Should I build a relationship? Should I visit the
factory? Should I be very strong on the price?’
What is your take on what works best
when dealing with a factory or supplier?
So it's an interesting question because
they're kind of all connected for us or for me,
especially when I was based in China, it's all
about establishing a relationship with them.
Factories really like it when you're
detail-oriented but flexible at the same
time. They love to be face to face with you, and
I think when you are building a strong personal
relationship with them, you're going to be able
to get into those flexible pricing discussions or
lead time discussions, but more importantly,
with a personal relationship with them.
By meeting with [factories] face to face, they're
going to start to give you preferential treatment,
or they might even just give you better
terms. I have some clients that we were
working with them for a year and a half and we
get like net 15 terms with them and we pass that
down to the client because the client, that
frees up their cash flow to do more marketing
and they could scale their business. So I
think it all starts with the relationship.
I think there's nothing wrong with
asking about price discounts. We do
it carefully because we don't want
them to think that we're just trying
to get the cheapest possible
price or anything like that.
But I'd say building a strong
relationship, being responsive,
keeping them in check. At the same time,
they like to know that you're going to be
systematic about things because then they
know you're an easy person to deal with.
When it comes to dealing with troubleshooting
issues, are you going to come up with solutions
with [the factory] to work through it? Sometimes
problems are not black and white. So being
flexible, having a good relationship, being
direct, is, I think, the most important part.
Yeah, so great. Let me chime in on that. So back
when I was running my own brands and I'm actually
working on some brands right now. I totally
agree that that face time—and it's not just
the FaceTime itself—but what that actually
enables that their relationship. Right at
the end of the day, it can be easy to think
that factories are just run like machines,
especially if you've never visited one
before or never worked with one directly.
They're not just run by machines. There may
be machinery, but a lot of the decisions,
the production runs are still run by people. And
there's a lot of manual decisions and there's a
lot of fluctuations and flexibility that can
actually be part of the process itself. And
therefore there can be a lot of leeway
in really pretty much everything. Now,
there's obviously limits, right? There's
limits on cost, there's limits on lead times,
there's limits on capacity, but within those
limits, there can be a lot of flexibility.
And this is where even if you as an end
client of a factory or sourcing agent,
and you may not have the largest orders,
but you're the one that's actually there,
and you're actually eating with them, drinking
with them, and building that relationship and
probably friendship with them as well, then
you're going to actually be able to get a lot
of things done that you normally would not
have, even if you have larger order volumes.
And this is probably also a part
of just the Chinese business
culture or the East Asian business culture.
Whether it is good or bad, relationships are
very important in Chinese business in general.
Now that doesn't mean that you as a DTC brand,
need to be at a factory all the time, but this
is one of the values of actually working with a
sourcing agent, someone that can be in the middle,
whether it's extension of your team or an agency
that you can actually trust to represent you, to
build and maintain those relationships as well.
100 percent agree with you. Every time I go
to China, it's just so many meetings with
factories and just getting that Facetime is so
valuable. And you build friendships. I mean,
that's the thing with doing business in China over
the years. And I'm sure both of you would agree
with this. It's like when you're doing business
over there [in China], [it’s like] you're entering
their family because even a lot of factories that
we're all working with are family-run operations.
So when you build that relationship with them,
they're inviting you to their
hometown for spring festival.
I can't begin to tell you how many spring
festivals I've had in the countryside with
like a factory owner, because we do a lot
of business together and they were like,
hey, you should come to my hometown and
we should drink and you should meet all
my cousins and relatives and you're
really just like part of their life.
And that is so different than the way
things are done in the United States and
Europe. And I think that's why I always
want to go back to China, just because I
really love how hospitable the culture
is there. So that would just be my final.
Yeah, definitely, definitely recognize
that when you get into that circle,
basically you're not going to leave that
circle again. You're part of it. It's not
so much of the family is not a real actual
biological family. It's whoever touches
is influencing your well-being or growth. So
it's very powerful to be part of that circle.
Definitely. When it comes to a lot of DTC brands
and a lot of people buying from China always
think, okay, the bigger the order, I need
to get lower prices as well. But obviously,
there are also some issues that come with getting
bigger orders means you have to pay much more
upfront. How would you say to deal better with
these kinds of cash flow issues to overcome this?
So since [we started] working with DTC brands,
I'd say we've been working heavily with them
over the last two and a half years now, where
we primarily just focus on working with them. I
think it's all about leveraging that historical
sales data and what the future holds for their
month-to-month volumes. So that you're actually
changing the conversation about, not about, hey,
I'm doing all this business with you, I need
to buy this much more so we can get to this
price. It's like: ‘no, how about over the next six
months I'm going to sell 200,000 units or more?’
And if you're just continuing to produce
for us every month, can we just have the
200,000 unit price? Of course, that's done over
dinner, meetings and stuff a lot of the time,
but that really is what it's about
because for my ecommerce clients,
mean ones that are doing fulfillment from China.
Try to keep a month or less of inventory and just
keep that factory churning product out and
getting it over to EcommOps, for example.
And then we just forecast the purchasing. I mean,
of course, there's going to be some things that
we have to negotiate with the factory, like,
hey, can you keep more bottles on hand or,
okay, you kind of need us to produce a little bit
more. So can you just keep some inventory at your
factory? And then we'll just do faster shipping
times, because as long as you're not dealing
with products that have short expiration dates,
which is not very common, then you're able to work
with the factory as well. And the factories
we work with are so big, they have space.
So I think it's just about trying
to find that happy medium between
fulfillment companies and the factory
and trying to produce smaller orders,
but still get the high volume price
because you have the sales to back it up.
Yeah, and I'll add to that as well. There
are a lot more variables to consider versus
just a simplified view of more ecos cheaper.
And usually, it takes longer as well. Right.
So when Greg is talking about maybe investing in
more bottles or other raw materials, for example,
that could actually just be a fraction, like a
small fraction of total cost that either you're
willing just to put a 10% extra deposit for those
materials, or the factory just absorbs it for you.
Right. And the other consideration is how often
do you actually need that stock replenishment?
So traditionally, if you're talking
about old-school traditional retail,
they're planning two to four
POs per year and massive POs,
right? And it's supposed to last them for
at least 3, 4, 5, 6 months. And a lot of
traditional factories, they're kind of used to
that model, so they kind of come with a standard
expectation of that. But that's actually not
exactly optimal for how a factory works as well.
No factory wants to just produce four
times a year, right? I mean, Greg,
I'm sure you agree with that, right? No factory
wants to produce just a couple times per year.
They have to crunch in order to do that. As a
matter of fact, they would actually prefer to.
What? The other extreme, actually, if they could
produce the exact same amount every single day
and not have to worry about their capacity
going up and down, that's the more ideal.
And actually, this is closer
to that ideal is what we see
when you're able to compress your lead time.
And we'll talk a little bit more about
that later. But that's one of the
biggest drivers that we've actually
seen. So either you're using air,
so you're having a way faster freight lead
time to your local fulfillment warehouse,
or more and more brands are just shipping
directly from China and being able to have
stock arrive at our Shenzhen warehouse in
like two days or one day or hours sometimes.
And what that means is that as opposed
to being forced to holding three,
four months inventory at a time,
they could actually hold three,
four days of inventory at a time. And this
is kind of what Greg was talking about.
You don’t work with a factory to
say ‘hey, I still want like two
months' worth of inventory. However, let's
figure out what your production schedule
is.’ And as opposed to taking a month
and a half to produce a massive batch,
does it actually make sense that you're actually
producing a much smaller amount every week,
every two weeks? And that might actually
be more optimal for the factory itself?
Yeah. And this ties in back as
well. Not only just the planning
itself of when do you release the
goods, but also the packaging.
Because if you're going to make the perfect
design of a product that is actually your
shipping air or it's not efficiently for an
air freight shipment. Because in the end,
everything is based on weight. So
that alignment on the actual supply,
as well as the efficiency and the
optimization on cost, placing a big
award, it doesn't necessarily create a healthier
cash flow situation, as well as the most optimal
supply chain that you could have, as well as
sometimes a discount can be in other areas.
Just by being more efficient on your
packaging, on the actual weight of the
product, as well as the timing on when
do you actually get shipments released
and the payment terms. This is exactly what
you said, right? Everyone wins in that sense.
Yeah. It's funny you say that, Simon, because we
were just having this conversation, you and me,
last week, with one of our clients, right. How
we needed to figure out what is a cost saving
solution for the client by making the packaging
smaller so it could fit into mailboxes. That way,
not only is he reducing some of his packaging
cost, but he's also reducing his shipping cost.
And it's funny you bring it up, because we were
just discussing our plan of attack after Chinese
new year this year, taking care of that. So
you're right. And this is why working with
you guys is just so key. Because you guys are able
to advise us as the sourcing agent dimensions and
how to make certain weights work just so that it's
more optimal for the client on the shipping side.
So I'll chime in there as well, because
I have a lot of omnichannel experience.
So thinking about retail displays, for example,
and this is where the packaging needs to be really
considered, how you're actually going to sell
it and how you're going to physically fulfill
it. A lot of factories for certain product
lines, skincare is a good example, actually.
They're more optimized for retail display.
I was actually just at a skincare factory that, I
mean, I was with your team, Greg, at the skincare
factory in Suzhou, and we were asking, so how
are you going, like what is the outside box?
We're looking at bottles and tubes and they
were like, we don't even think about that.
Our clients don't even ask about what the box
actually looks like. And I realized though,
because the bulk of their clients are actually
primarily producing for wholesale retail and
where the box doesn't really matter as
much as the display of the tube itself.
Right. However, let's take skincare as an
example. As more and more skincare brands go DTC,
you're going to actually require to consider
what is the right packaging actually for DTC
shipping. And if you don't have a hard
enough box that looks also nice enough,
it's going to break in shipping and it's
going to have a poor unboxing experience,
which is especially critical
for something like skincare.
Especially if you're selling at more of
a medium to higher price range, they're
going to be higher customer expectations
of how that package arrives as well.
So definitely make sure that you're also
thinking about the end customer experience,
what physical fulfillment method
that you're actually using,
and at least consider what type of
packaging is actually more ideal for
your fulfillment strategy and not just
what seems to be standard in the market.
Totally agree all about the unboxing experience
when it comes to being an ecommerce business.
Yeah, so we're really teaming up together,
EcommOps and Kanary Solutions. Actually,
what we're doing is building an ecosystem around,
at least in our case, around the fulfillment.
So you will see many more of our partners on the
podcast as well. But sourcing is so key that it
needs focus and attention. And you can see the
nuance already in our discussion when it comes
to packaging available supply, building up that
relationship and actually getting benefits out
of that relationship. That's not something that
a warehouse is built for to be able to also add
that service on top. That's why we work with
the best industry experts to help not only us,
our clients but also the industry, to bring
them up to the next level. And I don't know,
is there anything you would like
to share, maybe Dayu or Greg,
about what would be the benefits that we see
for brand owners the way we are approaching our.
So let me answer that first from my point
of view. EcommOps, when we first started,
it was really meant to be that next step from
drop shipping. So at the start, many years ago,
we also authored some simple sourcing services
as well now. And since quite a few years ago,
we've really shifted towards focusing our entire
focus on just fulfillment itself and not actually
acting as a more complex sourcing agent. And the
reason, from my point of view, is fundamentally,
there's such a huge difference from how a
very efficient sourcing company should be
set up versus a very efficient warehouse or three
po fulfillment centers should be set up for us.
And I'll speak about our experience first,
and I'll let Greg share the sourcing piece.
For EcommOps, everything has to be
optimized around extremely high volume,
high accuracy per package, a lot of integrations
and technology to make sure that we can just move
relatively simple pieces of work at a very
high volume as fast as possible and just
get it out the door on a daily basis. And
we just simply are not set up to have the
capabilities to have very deep, very complex
conversations with the factories themselves.
And this is where I personally think it's
actually impossible to be great at both
sides of the spectrum. So I say this because
especially if you're currently working as a
dropshipper or you're currently working with
a dropshipping agent who kind of does both.
And you think that that is an easier way of
doing things. I would just tell you that it's
easier probably right. But it's certainly
not nearly as efficient as you could be,
especially as you're scaling up your brand
and you wanted things to be more efficient.
And I'll let Greg talk about the
sourcing piece of the equation.
I think, I think you're totally right. You
really need to have your sourcing specialist
on the manufacturing side, and then you need
your fulfillment specialist on the shipping
side. And what I see a lot with DTC brands
is a lot of the clients that come over to us,
they're successful dropshipping businesses,
and they're primarily working with what you
would call a shipping agent. And they're having
their shipping agent source the product and ship
the product. And one of the problems with that is
it gives the shipping agent way too much control,
and it's also allowing them to pad
the prices on the sourcing too high.
We've seen shipping agents pad prices on
the sourcing side by upwards of 40 percent,
sometimes as high as 50 percent. And then
they're also shipping the product too,
and making their profits. So with
a dropshipping ecommerce store
coming over to us, we're giving them
more control over the manufacturing.
We are also talking directly with
the manufacturers. Whereas shipping
agents may just be buying from a
reseller or just some factory that
they chose instead of working
with [someone like] EcommOps.
What's been so great is we're saying,
hey, we're going to focus on your product,
and then on the back end, we're going to
be two companies under one roof, handling,
getting it over to the warehouse and making
sure they can tackle all your shipping needs.
So I think even just this tool that we're
launching, I'd say by the beginning of next month,
where we're tracking sales and inventory and being
able to forecast future purchasing, that really
allows us in ecommerce to work together as this
cohesive unit to help ecommerce brands make
better purchasing decisions that are going
to free up their cash flow. So I think there's a
lot of ways in our collaboration that's helpful
to the DTC brand. And also we're now giving them
more control over their back-end operations. They
may not realize it, but they do have a lot more
control because we know how to tackle prices
in our area. Just like how EcommOps is going to
know how to tackle prices in the shipping area.
Kind of just like what we were talking about
with that client that Simon and I were talking
about last week where we're trying to
reduce not just the packaging costs,
but the shipping costs by making it smaller.
Let me just take a step back and just look a
little bit from a bigger picture. Because the
industry has been changing you as a sourcing
guy. You have also been changed more from B2B
to focus on DTC. Working with DTC brands in the
industry is changing as well. Temu is coming,
Shein is there. Well, they're both there
already. But how is it impossible for
DTC brands to compete with players that
have a sophisticated sourcing network,
have the shipping, have the supply chain, and you
as a standalone DTC brand have to find your space.
What will be your angle on how
they can compete? I think both
your angles will be cool and interesting
to hear. So, Greg, maybe you can start.
I mean, I think Temu and Shein, they have
a different target market. They're selling
a lot of ancillary products. Or just
like, if it is electronics, it's simple.
They're being challenged to
customize their products,
improve their products and try to sell higher
value products, too. That way they can increase
their AOV or just their profit margin in
general. So I think what's really important,
and what I'm seeing with a lot of DTC brands
is they're starting to look at products that
have high customer retention rates so that they
can build this loyal customer base where they
can now start to sell these accessories that you
would see on Temu as like an upsell or cross-sell.
And they're just going to easily add it to
the cart because they're just always going
to that brand to buy the moisturizer from
them or it's like a supplement product or
something like that. So I think the way
to really compete with them is to build
a loyal customer base that's going to keep
coming back to you. That way you're able to
start selling those knickknacks that you're
seeing on Temu and Shein, and you're still
able to sell it for similar prices. Right. But now
you're buying it as a bundle with something, so
you're capturing that profit margin that you need
for those accessory, ancillary type of products.
So, I'm going to be a little bit blunt here,
and I would say that if you're seriously in
trouble of Shein or Temu outcompeting you,
then you're probably not actually running
a DTC brand. And the brand is the critical part
here. I mean, you might think you're running DTC.
I mean, you're selling directly to customers.
Right? But if you're doing that without the
actual brand element, then, yes, your pie
is going to be eaten by Shein or by, like,
I almost guarantee that actually, over
the long run, if that's all you're doing,
because then you're just kind of selling the
same stuff that they're going to be selling.
Temu is like the world's dollar store, right? It's
the world's Walmart [for] private label products,
right? So that's what they are. Now, not everyone
buys dollar-store stuff, right? We buy iPhones,
we buy stuff. We buy from brands that we
actually trust. We buy products from brands
that we actually engage with. But a big part
of that actually is not just the logo or the
front-end marketing, but it's actually everything
that you have associated with that customer.
And what is your brand relationship with
them now, it depends on your strategy,
but a lot of the time, and especially more and
more as she and Temu are getting more competitive.
It actually means going really deep and actually
thinking about how do you actually create a
customized experience, not just from marketing,
but actually from the products themselves,
and not just private labeling, but actually
creating and improving on your products.
And it's not that difficult. Right now, creating
something completely new is pretty difficult,
but if you're taking something that's on
the market already and you're actually
fundamentally improving it, it's actually not
that difficult. And I would actually argue that
if you don't do something like that, at least
for your core product offerings, now, obviously
you could do like, upsells cross sales. That's
a little bit different to increase your AOV.
But if you don't have some kind of
uniqueness in your core product offering,
then you don't really have a brand.
And I'll just be blunt again,
this is where the next couple of years, if
you don't actually do something like that,
then yes, you're probably not going
to compete with someone like Temu.
Yeah, I really second that. I think the days
of owning a store brand as like a DTC ecommerce
company are kind of ending because of them.
So I really do second what you're saying about
building a stronger brand. Let's just take a
red light therapy device, for example, or IPL
hair removal device. Those types of products
like you're not going to see on Shein or Temu,
because first of all, they're high-value ticket
items. And second of all, you need, like, FDA
certificates and like, five 10k certificates to
be able to import the product. So being able to
find the right product that is unique in
the market, that you're not seeing a lot
of people sell so that you could appear unique
and you're not creating something from scratch.
You're white labeling it, but you're seeing
that nobody else is really selling it.
That's definitely an easier way for you
to penetrate the market and be unique.
And then you're building this strong
brand like what you're saying, Dayu,
and then trying to get into those ancillary
products as like upsells cross-sells and
increasing that AOV so that you could be
profitable on those smaller products as well.
Yeah, the game has changed, and there might
be some more changes even in the game coming,
I would say. I know China is the factory of
the world, but we also see, and probably you
see as well, there's a shift in China where
some of the production is moving, maybe to
Southeast Asia. There's always the question
of, is that a threat? Is that an opportunity?
Do you have any take on how that would end
up or how this game is now being played?
So with traditional businesses we work with,
we have, we have come across a lot of this
shifting production over to Southeast Asia.
You have a lot of Chinese factories that are
setting up factories over there. But the
problem I'm seeing is it's really just the
large companies that are getting access to
that production. Because in Southeast Asia,
it's quite difficult to be doing small
batch orders for DTC brands, for example.
And also it depends on the industry. Like
Malaysia is getting bigger and bigger in
consumer electronics, but they still need to
import a lot of the materials from China to be
able to complete some of the production. So I
think overall Southeast Asia will continue to
be a player. I do think it's more with larger
scale production of things like take clothing,
it's going to be contract manufacturing to Nike
and stuff, versus some DTC brand that needs to
produce 500 or 1000 t-shirts type of thing. And
then I'm sure you guys can speak to this as well.
The fulfillment from those countries
like that setup is not even close to
as advanced as it is in China. So
I think it's a bit of way from an
SMB trying to produce stuff
in Southeast Asia right now.
Yeah, actually I actually just had a friend
who started a backpack brand and decided to
produce from Vietnam because of the lower
costs and he got killed by freight costs.
So basically all of the cost savings that he
had were essentially just completely nullified
because of the addition of supply chain costs,
of actually getting out of means, regardless what
it means, either it's this decision or
really anything else in the supply chain.
One suggestion I have everyone is don't think
about costs in a vacuum. Don't just look at
production costs, don't just look at logistics
costs, packaging costs. You have to consider
everything altogether and also consider against
your balance sheet risk, how much cash are you
getting tied up. Consider all these financial
levers together and many times you'll actually see
that just by optimizing one tiny little area of
your production or supply chain, you're actually
potentially damaging or slowing down other areas
and at a net basis, it could actually be worse.
Very awesome. That's really
interesting. So regarding this episode,
what do you want the listener to
remember after this episode? What
do you think? Do you want people to have
their perspective on sourcing from China?
I think there's two points. I would say. The first
point, this would be more for the drop shippers. I
think working with shipping agents is dangerous
for them handling your sourcing and fulfillment
at the same time because they have a lot more
control over your pricing. So in a way, they
become kind of inflexible with helping you develop
products as a result. The other piece that I have
is for ecommerce businesses that are already
set up and working with fulfillment companies.
I'd say the big takeaway goes back to
what I was saying about the due diligence,
is really make sure that you are working
directly with the manufacturer so you're
set up for a long-term relationship with them. The
last thing you really want to know or find out,
and this happens a lot with our clients, is
that you were working with a trade company
this entire time, and you weren't really building
any kind of relationship with the actual factory.
So I would say that's like, the other big piece
to walk away from is making sure
you know who you're working with.
Dayu, what do you take away from this episode?
Yeah. So I would like everyone to take away
that there is an actual supply chain that
you should be aware of or managing and
depending on what stage of the business
you are. So if you're a dropshipper, realize
that there is a lot that actually happens,
that there is actually a supply
chain that you should be aware of,
and you should actually be thinking about
breaking your supply chain into steps as well.
And even if you're more advanced, like
if you're a DTC ecommerce brand already,
and maybe you actually work with a sourcing agent,
maybe you have contacts with factories already,
realize that there are a lot deeper nuances,
a lot more drivers, a lot more complexity in
a good way. I think that you can actually affect
if you build that strong relationship with your
supply chain, understand that there is a lot
of flexibility, that not everything is robotic.
And being able to work with your suppliers or
with your sourcing agent or factory directly
to figure out more creative solutions that
you can partner together to actually achieve
mutually beneficial goals for both your
brand and also your suppliers as well.
Awesome. For me, it's really the bigger companies
get bigger, the smaller get smaller. So you have
to focus somewhere. And for us, focusing on
sourcing or focusing on pure fulfillment,
that's where you're going to
excel. At least that's my opinion.
Thank you so much, Greg, for joining us.
Thank you, Dayu, for being here as well.
Thank you, listeners. Hope
to see you on the next one.
Thank you so much for listening to the EcommOps
podcast. It was a pleasure having you here today.
Don't forget to like, subscribe, and follow this
podcast. This was awesome about sourcing from
China. It's crucial for any DTC brand buying from
China. Hope you enjoyed it. Hope you have tons of
takeaways. If you do, please do let us know. Feel
free to reach out to Greg or EcommOps itself.
Hope to see you on the next one.